你们生来非凡 我的孩子们
You are extraordinary, my sons.
超脱世人的认知
Unlike anything the world has ever seen.
注定成就伟大
Bound for greatness.
注定要保护纽约的人民
Destined to protect the people of New York.
一股黑暗势力正在发展壮大
A dark force is growing.
就是一个名为"大脚帮"的犯罪组织
A criminal organization known as the Foot Clan.
他们因肆意践踏
So named because they step over
纽约人民而得名
the good people of this city with no regard.
他们的头目 施莱德
Their leader, The Shredder,
将会残忍袭击你们
will come at you with ferocity.
他的爪牙人多势众
His Foot Clan will outnumber you.
纽约人民将把你们视作唯一的希望
The people of New York will look upon you as their only hope.
集中精力
Eyes focused.
收紧双肘
Elbows locked.
准备战斗
Stance low.
即刻行动
And we begin.
与剑合二为一
Be one with the blades.
扫清前路
Lead their path.
我知道你们已经迫不及待想倾听他们的诉求
I know you are eager to answer their calls,
但你们的训练仍未结束
but your training is not yet complete.
地下世界仍为你们的居所
The world below must remain your home.
你们必须信任我 你们的父亲
As your father, you must trust me.
耐心等待
Patience.
潜心修炼
你们仍未准备好进入城市
You're not yet ready to go above ground.
但我相信当那天来临时
But I believe when that day comes
当你们走上地面
and you rise to the streets,
你们将会做出
you are going to be responsible
一番伟大的事业
for amazing things.
《忍者神龟：变种时代》
利维迪先生
Mr. Rivetti!
利维迪先生 利维迪先生 求您了
Mr. Rivetti. Mr. Rivetti, please.
你绝对是我这辈子
You're the most persistent human
见到过的最难缠的人
I've ever met in my life, I swear.
我已经把知道的都告诉警察了
Look, I already told the cops everything, all right?
但也有可能
But maybe there's a detail
你漏了一点细节忘记说了呢
you could've forgotten to share with the police.
美女 这种事我不可能会忘的
Sweetheart, you don't forget something like that.
光天化日的 十个人强闯进来
Ten guys storm in here, broad daylight,
用枪指着我们让我们趴地上
force us to the ground at gunpoint.
这些都是机密化学品
And these are restricted chemicals.
苄基氰还有脱氨基剂什么的
Benzyl cyanide and some deaminating agents, too.
市面上根本买不到 黑市都买不到
You don't just buy this stuff, even on the black market.
等等 你刚刚说到脱氨基剂
Wait, you said deaminating agents,
那是用于基因研究的
those are used in genetic research.
除了你
Is there anybody else
还有别人运输这种化学品吗
that's trafficking these sort of chemicals besides you?
这码头上还有另一家 戒备很森严
There's one other high-security facility along this waterfront.
但他们的运输量没我们的大
But they don't move nearly as much cargo as we do.
奥尼尔 半小时后就要直播了 快点成吗
O'Neil! We're live in 30 minutes! Come on!
不不不 我马上回来
Uh... No, no, no, I'll be right back.
请等我一会儿 我很快就回来
Please don't go anywhere. I'll be right back.
拜托 你想害死我吗
Come on, you're killing me.
我在做事呢
I'm working.
- 有钱拿吗 - 没
- That's a paying job? - No.
有钱拿的事都还没做
Because we have an actual paying job.
你不觉得市里每一个报道犯罪的记者
Look, you don't think that every crime reporter
都在拼命挖大脚帮的故事吗
in the city has been trying to work this Foot Clan story?
我知道 但有一个新的角度
I know that, but there is a new angle on this,
我很快就要挖到了
and I am this close to getting it.
只需要一点…
I just need a couple of more...
我们还是专注做好我们擅长的事吧
Let's just stick to what we're good at.
专注做好我们擅长的事就好了 我们可厉害了
Let's stick to what we're good at. We're good at it.
五 四…
In five, four...
大家好 我是第六新闻频道的爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
Hi, guys, this is April O'Neil from Channel 6 News
此刻我在美丽的纽约市
and I am here in beautiful New York City
就在初春第一天
on the first day of spring.
你们知道我想说什么
And you know what that means.
又到了甩掉烦人冬膘的时候啦
It is time to shed that pesky winter weight.
今天我们的嘉宾
And here with me today
是著名的健身教练哈里·帕斯特纳克 你好啊
is celebrity fitness trainer Harley Pasternak. Hi, Harley.
早上好 爱普莉尔
Good morning, April.
二十年前我研究过动物王国
Twenty years I've studied the animal kingdom.
里边有肥猪和胖牛
There are fat pigs, there are fat cows.
却没有胖鸟
There are no fat birds.
好 你现在设想自己是一只性感的海鸥
All right, I want you to visualize a sexy seagull.
我们要蹲下挥动你的翅膀
So we're going to squat down and flap your wings.
就这样 最大限度去摆动
Right over there. Full extension.
想象你正在飞离寒冷的北方
Picture you're leaving the cold north
挥动翅膀 你正在迁移
and you're flying. You're migrating.
念了四年新闻专业就为了做这个
Four years of journalism school so that I can do that.
整整四年啊 弗恩
Four years of my life, Vern.
太丢人了
It's embarrassing.
好了 奥尼尔 我明白
Look, O'Neil, I get it,
你想当一名正经的记者
you want to be a serious journalist.
我看到你在新闻编辑室附近转悠找大新闻
I see you sniffing around the newsroom for the big stories.
但给人们带来一些轻松的东西
But it's also okay to just give people something
一点…新闻白沫也不错啊
a little lighter. A little... little froth.
新闻白沫
Froth?
新闻白沫就是 比如你拿一杯普普通通的咖啡
You know, how, when you get a coffee, it's just, like, coffee,
加点白沫在面上的话 就显得更好看更好喝
then they put a little froth on it. It's kind of nice.
弗恩 那叫泡沫
Vern, that's foam.
对啊 管它泡沫还是白沫 反正你懂的
Yes, foam, froth, you get the point.
反正很好看很美味像糖一样甜
It's just... It's nice, it tastes good, it's candy.
你没听别人说吗
You ever heard the expression,
"永远不要抢走孩子的糖"
"Never take candy from a baby"?
因为就连孩子都喜欢吃糖啊
It's because even babies love candy!
美味就行 你就是在给予人们
It's nice. And you're giving people
他们所喜欢的又好又美味的东西
something they like that's good and nice.
他们看着你就在想
They look at you and they see,
"哇 这真是一个美丽的 的…
"Wow, there's a nice... There's...
甜妞" 总之重点是
"...candy". The point is,
我觉得你应该得到嘉奖啊
I think that you should be rewarded,
别老虐自己 好吗
not punishing yourself. Okay?
所以我准备奖励你
And I'm... I'm prepared to reward you.
我们去市中心吧 去我兄弟的老餐馆搓一顿
I say that we go to my buddy's old restaurant downtown.
那里气氛挺好…
It's very vibey...
我们来这儿的路上刚吃过了
We just ate on the way over here.
这我知道… 我是说 不吃正餐
No, I know we just... I'm not saying for a full meal,
去吃点儿开胃菜什么的
we're just gonna eat appetizers.
我得去把采访做完
I got to go finish that interview.
办公室见 弗恩
I'll see you at the office, Vern!
回见吧你
I will see you at the office!
我想继续采访你 利维迪先生
I just wanted to follow up, Mr. Rivetti.
搞什么 你怎么弄到我号码的
Are you kidding me? How did you get my number?
我只想再问一个问题
If I could just ask one more question...
这个案子我已经把知道的全告诉你了
Listen, I already told you everything I know about this crime,
- 所有的 - 等等
- everything. - Wait, wait, wait.
好吧 你想知道别的
Okay, you wanna know anything else,
就回码头去找一个叫斯坦的人
you go back down to the docks and you see my guy Stan.
你想知道的他都会告诉你
He'll tell you anything else you need to know, okay?
还有 行行好
And hey, do me a favor.
把我的号码删掉好吗
Lose my number, all right?
没错
Good.
安全 都打开
It's clear. Let's open it up.
(硝基乙烷)
罐子没问题 继续搬
Container's good. Move on to the next one.
都弄出来
Move it out!
全装上车
Get those to the trucks now!
走 去下一个地方 快快快
Move out, next point! Go, go, go.
好了
We're done.
- 第六频道 - 克里斯
- Channel 6. - Chris.
克里斯 我是爱普莉尔 我在码头这里
Chris, it's April. I'm at the docks.
这大半夜的 奥尼尔
We're at the middle of the evening break O'Neil.
无论什么新闻都等明天吧
Whatever you got can wait for tomorrow.
不不 我看到化学品…
No, no, I see chemical...
2-3-2 安全
2-3-2, clear!
- 都弄走 - 明白
- Get it out of my way. - Copy that.
(光线过暗)
该死
Damn it.
第二小队 第三区 走
Unit two, area three, move!
这边有动静
I've got movement!
注意这里
Keep your eyes over here!
允许开火
Weapons free!
都别动
Hold position!
撤退
Retreat!
撤退 离开这里
Retreat! Get out of here!
快走
Move! Move!
泰勒 泰勒
Taylor. Taylor!
我在和我妈聊天呢
Hey. I'm Skyping with my mom.
你不会相信我刚刚看到了什么
You have no idea what I just went through.
吓死我了 我看到有人袭击大脚帮
I am freaking out. I saw a Foot Clan attack.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我在码头边上骑自行车
I was riding my bike by the docks.
晚上天都黑了
It was night, it's dark already
那里到处都是大脚帮的人
and there are Foot Clan soldiers everywhere.
接着不知道从哪儿出来一个人
Then out of nowhere, there was this guy
开始对抗他们
fighting back against them.
还留下了一个标志
And he... he left behind this symbol.
我以前肯定见过
And I know that I've seen it before.
但我不记得了
I can't remember where.
但的的确确有人在对抗大脚帮
But there is someone fighting back against the Foot Clan.
城里出现了正义卫士
There is a vigilante in this city.
没人知道 除了我
And no one knows, but I do.
我知道 现在我找到大新闻了
I know. And now I have my story.
我要和白沫和泡沫说拜拜
There is no more froth and foam for me.
啥
What?
没什么
Never mind.
今晚的新闻头条 有谁有想法吗
All right, we need a lead for tonight. Who's got it?
曼哈顿下城区重建提案
"Major redevelopments proposed for Lower Manhattan."
不行
No.
我这儿有
I got something.
纽约警署特遣队降低了大脚帮犯罪率
"NYPD task force taking credit for small decline in Foot-related crime."
- 不错 就用这个 - 明白
- I like that. Let's run with that. - Yes, ma'am.
早七点新闻
7:00 am broadcast,
还有三分钟开始
we have three minutes to air.
奥尼尔 我一会儿再和你谈
Oh, O'Neil. I'll talk to you in a minute.
我知道我跑这儿来
I know that I'm actually overstepping
是越线了
my boundaries by being here,
但我觉得你会…
but I think that you're gonna...
我觉得你们所有人
I actually think that you're
都会想听我接下来要说的话
all gonna want to hear what I have to say.
昨晚在布鲁克林我亲眼目睹了
Um, I witnessed an attempted Foot Clan robbery
大脚帮在码头想偷窃东西
at the docks in Brooklyn last night.
等等 是有人听到枪声
Hold on, the scanner said that gunshots were heard,
但没有任何大脚帮活动的相关报道
but there were no reports of any Foot Clan activity.
那是因为他们被人制止了
That's because whatever they were attempting to do was stopped.
话说你去布鲁克林做什么
What were you doing in Brooklyn anyway?
那里有蹦床大会吗
Was there a trampoline convention?
我去布鲁克林是因为我在追踪报道
I was in Brooklyn because I was reporting,
而不是干坐在办公桌后面 麦克诺顿
not sitting behind my desk, McNaughton.
好了你们
Okay, kids!
谁阻止了他们
Who stopped it?
有这么个人
Well, there was this guy.
我没看清 但他抡起了
I didn't see him clearly, but he was swinging
巨大的运输集装箱
these giant shipping containers
把那些家伙撞进了…河里
and knocking these guys into the... into the river.
有一名正义卫士在
There is a vigilante that is fighting back
抗击大脚帮 这可是个大新闻啊
against the Foot Clan. There's a huge story here!
奥尼尔 你可能看到了超人啊 太厉害了
O'Neil, I think you found Superman. That's cool.
真的有正义卫士 我看到他了
The vigilante is real. I saw him.
奥尼尔 我得说
O'Neil, I'm gonna assume
如果没有确切的证据
that you would not come up here
你不能就这么跑到这里
and tell us this fantastic story
告诉我们这个奇幻故事
without some tangible proof.
我拍下了其中一个集装箱的照片
I took this photo of one of the shipping containers.
我觉得这就是他在场的证据
I actually think that it may be his calling card.
这什么都不是 奥尼尔 什么都没有
This is nothing, O'Neil. This is nothing!
这就是关键
That's exactly the point.
有人阻止了大脚帮却没留下证据
Somebody stopped a Foot robbery and left no evidence.
什么都没有
There is nothing.
我知道了
Oh, I get it.
你想让我把"什么都没有"
You wanted me to put "Nothing"
- 放到晚间新闻上是吧 - 当然不是
- on the nightly news. - Of course not.
我就当你什么都没说
You know, I'm gonna pretend we never had this conversation.
我什么都不知道
I'm erasing it from my mind.
其他人动起来 开工了
And the rest of us, we're gonna go back to work.
我们走
Let's hit it!
好 头条新闻准备就绪
OK, we're ready for the topic story.
大家好 欢迎收看第六频道早间新闻
Hello, everybody. Welcome to the Channel 6 Morning News.
大家将看到有关卫生罢工的最新进展
New developments in that ongoing sanitation strike to tell you about.
但首先 在与警察局长共同反思了
But first, after reviewing the city's soaring crime rates
城内上升的犯罪率之后
with the police commissioner,
丹·格雷戈尔议员在市政厅采取举措
Councilman Dan Gregor took to the steps of City Hall,
重申了纽约城
reaffirming the city's commitment
打击犯罪组织的决心
to fight against the rising crime organization
该犯罪组织名为大脚帮
calling themselves the Foot Clan.
这是在他与埃里克·赛克斯以及赛克斯企业
He did so on the heels of a renewed
重新签订相关合同之后采取的举措
contract with Eric Sacks and Sacks Industries.
利用赛克斯的研究以及安全技术
Using the Sacks research and securities technology,
纽约城抗击大脚帮的成功率
this city greatly improves its chances
将会大大增加
of bringing the Foot Clan to justice!
[日语] 开始
[日语] 你的人太弱了
[日语] 难怪你会失败
我们不知道那个所谓的正义卫士
We couldn't have anticipated the vigilante
会在码头出现 施莱德大师
showing up at the docks, Master Shredder.
[日语] 你们不是训练过怎样应对这种突发情况吗?
但我们从未见过那样的敌人
But we've never seen an enemy like this.
他们的身形
Their size.
还有力量都前所未见
Their strength.
他们不是人类
They're not human.
我不相信神话故事
I don't believe in fairy tales.
社会倒是想把大脚帮也变成那样
It's what society wants to reduce the Foot Clan to.
变成传说
A myth.
但大脚帮
But the Foot Clan
会东山再起
will rise again.
无论如何都要把正义卫士抓住
Capture the vigilantes however you can.
用无辜的人当诱饵
Use innocent people as bait.
没有人能阻止我们
No one will stop us in our quest
重获胜利
to reclaim victory.
我们会拿下这座城市
We will own this city.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请允许我为您介绍纽约警局的最大资助人
please join me in welcoming the NYPD's top benefactor,
埃里克·赛克斯
Eric Sacks.
谢谢大家
Please, please. Please.
请坐 请坐
Sit down, sit down.
我想说
I have to say,
今晚能够见到诸位 我感到不胜荣幸
it's wonderful to see so many people out here tonight,
尤其是我们这里一直苦于
especially in a neighborhood so hard hit
大脚帮的残虐暴行
by the Foot's crime wave.
几年前 我的人生遭遇了悲剧
Years ago, my life was touched by tragedy.
我曾是一名年轻的科学家 与顶级团队合作
I was a young scientist working with a world-class team
做最前沿的研究
on cutting-edge research.
可我们的实验室被人袭击
And our laboratory was attacked,
被人放火 抢劫
set fire to, robbed,
凶手就是那些自称为大脚帮的懦夫
by the cowards that call themselves the Foot Clan.
我的几位员工
Several of my employees
在那天失去了生命
lost their lives that day.
以铭记他们 向他们致敬的名义
And it is in their honor, in their memory,
赛克斯企业 不论是赛克斯生物医学公司
that Sacks Industries, whether through Sacks Biomed,
赛克斯机器人科学公司 或是赛克斯建筑公司
Sacks Robotics or Sacks Construction,
一定会保证我们这座城市 纽约
to keeping the city of New York, our city,
安然无恙
safe.
不论谁将这座城市置于险境
So whenever someone takes flame to this city,
我都会救其于危难之中
I will be there to put the fire out.
我向各位保证
And that's a promise.
谢谢 谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you.
先生您讲得真好 非常鼓舞人心
Great work, sir. Very inspirational.
塞克斯先生 我是爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
Mr. Sacks. April O'Neil.
您以前跟我父亲是同事
You worked with my father.
是吗
Oh!
简直难以置信 我上次见你是在…
I can't believe it. I haven't seen you since...
是在父亲的葬礼上
Since his funeral.
很久之前的事了
It was a long time ago.
是啊
Yeah.
我只是想跟您说
I just wanted to tell you
您的话让我产生了很大的共鸣
that your words really resonated with me,
我希望有一天
and I hope to one day
也能像您一样为这个城市做贡献
contribute to the city in the way that you do.
你现在已经做得很不错了
Well, it looks like you're doing a pretty good job.
第六频道 厉害啊 爱普莉尔
Channel 6, very impressive, April.
谢谢 其实…
Thank you. It's, uh...
那并不完全是我期待的生活
it isn't exactly everything I anticipated it would be.
只要你坦诚正直
As long as you are true to yourself,
你父亲就会为你自豪的
your father will always be proud of you.
赛克斯先生 您7点要去上城区
Mr. Sacks, we have to be uptown at 7:00.
期待在电视上看到你
I'll see you on TV.
埃里克·赛克斯太鼓舞人心了
Eric Sacks was so inspiring.
我知道这个故事肯定很重要
I know this is a story that actually matters.
超级英雄那个吗
The superhero one?
真是个好主意 我应该去跟进下
That's a good idea. I should chase that down.
大家这是要去哪里
Where's everybody going?
奥尼尔 你要去哪里
O'Neil! Where are you going?
- 爱普莉尔 - 请问出了什么事 等一下
- April! - Hey! What are you running from? Wait, wait!
有人开枪 百老汇和中心街交界处
Shots fired, Broadway and Centre Street.
监控录像显示
Surveillance upper lens are showing heavy
在百老汇舞台附近有大批大脚帮在活动
heavy Foot Clan activity at the Broad Street platform.
还到处抓人质…
And taking hostages with them...
你知道我们不能随便上去的
But you know we're not supposed to go above ground.
我以前也这么干过
I've done this before.
做事情要有始有终
We started something, we gotta finish it.
太疯狂了
This is insane.
这猫在用筷子弹《筷子曲》
That cat is playing Chopsticks with chopsticks!
别犯蠢了
Don't be an idiot.
- 诶呀 - 好了
- Aw. - Okay.
开始行动吧 兄弟们
Let's rock 'n' roll, boys!
快跑
Run!
快离开
Get out!
快走
Go, go!
(请勿乱扔垃圾)
要是不想死 就快点 快点
If you want to live, do it! Go on!
趴下
Just stay down!
过来
Get over here!
继续走
Keep moving!
把手举到我能看见的地方
Keep your hands where I can see them!
退到边上去
Move to the side.
- 是炸弹 - 闭嘴
- They're bombs. - Shut up!
趴下
On the ground!
都不许动
Nobody move!
我们知道你在这里
We know you're out there!
要是不出来投降 我们就开始处决人质
If you don't surrender, we start executing hostages!
低下头 不许动
Get your head down! Don't move!
别让我再说一次 闭嘴
Don't make me tell you again! Not a word!
别看我
Don't look at me!
不要 不要
Don't! Don't do it!
你
You!
站起来
Stand up!
来啦
All aboard!
[日语] 行动
快
Come on!
就是这样
That's right.
来无影去无踪
Like a shadow, bra.
走 快走
Let's go! Let's move!
- 他们往那边去了 - 你看到了吗
- They went that way! - Did you see what happened here?
他们刚刚从这里爬上去了
They were climbing up here.
- 就这里 - 什么怪物
- Right here. - Some kind of freak!
好像有好几个
There were a couple of them!
瞬间经过我
Whoo! Right past me!
他们救了我们
They saved us.
走 快走
Go, go, go!
行动起来 两边包抄
Let's go, guys! Both sides!
太棒了 干得漂亮
That was amazing. You were incredible!
手肘一击不错哦 多尼
Great elbow, Donnie.
哥说的就是这个感觉
Oh, yeah! That's what I'm talking about.
这是我们的城市 我们的街道
This is our city! These are our streets!
敢挑衅我们 就准备受死吧
You mess with us, you step into the Wu!
直接秒杀
Whoo, Tang!
爽 看到那货下巴直接磕地上了吗
Ooh, yeah! Did you see that guy's jaw connect with the concrete?
估计几个月喝水都得用吸的了
He'll be drinking out of a sippy cup for months!
我要的就是这感觉 兄弟们
Ah, that's what I'm talking about, brothers.
来无影去无踪 没人看到
Like shadows in the night. Completely unseen.
刚刚好像是闪光灯
It's a camera flash.
废话 问题是闪光灯后面是谁
We know it's a camera flash. Who's behind the camera flash?
据我目测 是个女的
By my calculations, it's a girl.
- 我去处理掉她 - 什么
- I'm gonna kill her. - What?
用善意处理啦 送点花 博得好感
With kindness, give her some flowers, earn her trust.
- 我来吧 - 拉斐 不要 拜托
- I got this. - Raph, no, no, no! Come on!
把相机给我
Give me the camera.
哟 他学蝙蝠侠说话呢
Ooh, look, he's doing his Batman voice.
她好漂亮 我的龟壳都发紧了
She's so hot, I can feel my shell tightening.
我们听得见
We can hear you!
要是不把相机给我
If you don't give me the camera,
我就…
I'm gonna...
够了
Enough!
退下 拉斐
Back off, Raph.
我就见过蝙蝠侠一面
I only saw Batman once!
姑娘你好 非常抱歉
Ma'am, hello. I apologize.
我的这位同事忘记说"请"了
My colleague here forgot to say "Please."
所以
So,
能不能请你把相机交出来
would you please hand over the camera?
没事 没事 别怕
No, no, no, no. Whoa.
别怕 只是个面具而已 你看 别害怕
Whoa. Chill. It's just a mask. See? Don't freak out.
对吧
Right?
我的安慰很有效嘛
Oh, I think that went well.
呼吸稳定 血压逐渐回落
Breathing steady. Blood pressure stabilizing.
我们为啥要在这儿装医生
Why are we still here playing doctor?
她脑袋可能受伤了
She may have a head injury.
纠正一下 一位美女的脑袋可能受伤了
Uh, correction. She's a hot chick who may have a head injury,
所以我们的职责就是…
which makes it, our civic duty to...
姑娘 姑娘
Ma'am, ma'am.
听得到我说话吗 你知道你在哪座城市吗
Can you hear me? Do you know what city you're in?
你知道你在哪里吗
Do you know where you are?
你有看过那个视频吗
Have you seen that video where the cat
一只猫用筷子弹奏《筷子曲》那个
plays Chopsticks with the chopsticks?
别捣乱了
Can we focus here?
行了 都离远点 给点新鲜空气
Guys, please! Come on. Give her some air.
你们是什么
What are you?
这位姑娘
Well, Miss,
我们是忍者
uh, we're ninjas.
我们是变种
We're mutants.
严格意义上来说 我们是乌龟
Well, technically, we're turtles.
而且我们还是青少年哦
Oh, and we're teenagers!
不过聊点成人话题也是可以的
But we can still have adult conversations.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait. So...
你们是
You're...
忍者 变种
Ninja, mutant,
乌龟 青少年
turtle, teenagers?
你这么一说 感觉好荒谬
Well, when you put it like that, it sounds ridiculous!
你看 她一副看见变态的表情
See, she's looking at us like we're freaks.
所以你才拍我们的照片 对吗
I bet that's why you took our picture, wasn't it?
为了给朋友看
To show your friends?
兄弟 这是好事 说不定她朋友也很漂亮呢
Bro, that's a good thing! Maybe she has hot friends.
- 你在找这个吗 - 别弄坏
- Looking for this? - Don't break it.
不 不要
No, no, no. Please.
我要跟你说多少次
How many times do I have to tell you?
我们不搞破坏 搞维修
We don't break things, we fix them.
多尼已经都删干净了 你个呆子
Donnie already wiped the phone, genius.
问题解决了 走吧
Problem solved, moving on.
- 凭什么你说了算 - 你知道凭什么
- And who put you in charge? - You know who did.
又剑拔弩张了 半小时前
Ooh, tension! It's been like 30 whole minutes
你们就吵过这个话题了
since you guys had this argument.
李奥纳多 要是想赶在师父前回到家
Leonardo, if we want to make it home before Master,
最好抓紧时间
we gotta hustle.
李奥纳多
Leonardo?
不要把这些事告诉任何人
Do not say a word about this to anyone.
否则 我们会去找你
If you do, we will find you.
爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
April O'Neil.
走吧 拉斐尔
We're on the move, Raphael.
拉斐尔
Raphael?
没错
Yeah!
我们会去找你的 奥尼尔
We'll find you, O'Neil.
抱歉 刚刚语气加得有点过了
I'm sorry, that came across super creepy, okay?
我们会去找你的哦
We will find you, though.
我刚刚简直帅呆了
I was on fire, bro!
你看到我的表现了吗
Did you see me back there?
我居然跟一个女生说话了
Guys, I totally talked to a girl!
闭嘴 麦奇
Shut up, Mikey!
兄弟们
Yeah, bra!
麦奇 是你放的吗
Mikey, was that you?
意大利腊香肠味儿哦
Pepperoni.
李奥纳多 我见过这些名字 我见过的
Leonardo. I know those names. I know those names.
拉斐尔 拉斐尔 李奥纳多
Raphael, Raphael. Leonardo.
(实验笔记)
(实验室火灾害死科学家)
(文艺复兴项目)
晚上好
Good evening.
我是爱普莉尔·奥尼尔
This is April O'Neil,
正在我爸爸的实验室进行记录
reporting live from my daddy's lab.
我知道实验室听起来很无聊
I know it sounds pretty boring,
不过其实 他的研究还是挺炫酷的
but actually, he does some pretty cool stuff.
把相机收起来吧 爱普莉尔
Time to put the camera away, April.
爸爸
Aw, Dad!
接下来就是
And now I will show you
见证奇迹的时刻
something amazing.
据说这是来自外太空的
It's supposed to be from a different planet
- 一个其它星球哦 - 来看看
- in outer space! - Here we go.
赛克斯先生
Mr. Sacks,
请问你在做什么样的实验呢
what sort of experiments are you doing here?
你这个问题太复杂了
Oh, that's a very complicated question.
我们是在努力改变世界
We're trying to change the world.
看着相机说
Look at the camera!
你好啊 斯普林特
Hello, Splinter.
(李奥纳多)
这些是我的小乌龟 李奥纳多
And these are my little turtles, Leonardo,
拉斐尔
Raphael,
米开朗琪罗和多纳泰罗
Michelangelo and Donatello.
粉丝们想见见你们
The fans want to see you!
我就知道
I knew it.
正义卫士 我看到了 我看到他们了
The vigilante, I saw him. I saw them! I saw them.
我从小就认识他们
I've known them since I was a little girl.
他们曾是我的宠物
They were my pets.
他们曾是我小时候的宠物
They were my childhood pets,
他们的名字是按照文艺复兴时期的意大利画家起的
and they were named after Italian Renaissance painters.
妈妈 我想搬回家里
Mom, I want to move back home.
他在吗
Is he here?
没看见
I don't see him.
多尼
Donnie?
我的热扫描器显示有74%的变量
My thermal scans indicate there's a 74% variable
也就是有61%的可能…
that there's a 61% chance he's not...
他不在这里 兄弟们
That he's not here, guys.
他不在这里
That he's not here.
好吧
Okay.
前进 保持安静
Fall in, quietly.
拜托
Dude.
以防我之前表现得不够明显 那妞
So, guys, if it wasn't already obvious with that girl,
我要了
dibs.
要是被斯普林特大师发现了
If Master Splinter catches us,
他会把我们送回边端
he'll send us back to the Ha'shi.
我可不要回边端
I ain't going back to the Ha'shi.
我们每次进边端 都是因为你
Every time we're in the Ha'shi, it's because of you.
行了 以后你再也不用担心
Well, bro, you won't have to worry about me
我会拖你后腿了
dragging you down anymore.
什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我要单干 一有机会就单干
I'm going out on my own. First chance I get.
那我们创作到一半的嘻哈圣诞节专辑怎么办
How are we gonna finish our hip-hop Christmas album, bro?
全靠你撑场子啊
You're the hype man!
闭嘴
Shut up.
都闭嘴
谁唾沫进我眼睛里了
I got glop in my eye.
别吵 他哪儿也不许去 我们要一起行动
Shh! He's not going anywhere. We all stick together.
抱歉我喷你眼睛里了
Sorry I spit in your eye, bro.
各位 各位
Shh! Guys? Guys.
我们被发现了
We got a bogey.
你们去哪里了
Where have you been?
我们没有…
We weren't...
我忘了泡我的牙套了
I forgot to soak my retainer!
我只是在梦游
I'm totally sleepwalking!
看呐 麦奇边睡觉边走路
Look, Mikey's sleeping and walking.
他是无辜的
He's totally innocent.
够了 你们违背了命令
Enough! You disobeyed a direct order.
你们为什么去地面上 发生了什么
Why did you go above ground? What happened?
很好
Very well.
如果你们一定要这样的话
If that's how it's going to be,
去边端
to the Ha'shi!
(犯罪现场)
奥尼尔
O'Neil!
好了 有什么事非得我亲自过来
All right, what was so important I had to get here?
- 好的 你准备好了吗 - 是的
- Okay. Are you ready? - Yeah.
- 你知道我看到了正义卫士吧 - 对
- Okay. You know how I saw the vigilante? - Yeah.
但是我没有照片或者其他的证据
But I had no photos or evidence to show you,
- 所以你觉得我疯了 - 是的
- so I just sounded crazy. - Yes.
好的 但是我又见到了他
Okay. But I saw him again.
其实并不是他
Well, I didn't see him again,
我看到了他们 因为总共有四个
I saw them, because there's four.
不止一个 是四个 并且我就这样
There's not just one, there's four. And I was standing
跟他们面对面对视过
as close to them as you are to me right now.
他们长什么样
What'd they look like?
你看
I'll show you.
什么
What?
就像这样
Like this.
像乌龟一样
Like turtles?
他们并不是看起来像乌龟
Well, they don't look like turtles
因为他们就是乌龟
because they are turtles.
他们身高超过1米83 并且会说英语
They're over six feet tall and they speak English.
哦 天呐
Oh, my God.
我整夜都没睡 请你看一下 我整夜都没睡
I was awake all night, please look, I was awake all night
一直在查过去三个月内
googling all of the thwarted crimes
他们阻止的犯罪 还有这个符号
over the past three months, and this symbol
在每个犯罪现场都出现了
appeared at every single one.
看 真的是每一个都有
Look! Every single one of them.
这个 看 这里 这里 这里
This one, look. Here, here, here, here, here.
这是古老的日语词汇 代表家
And it's an ancient Japanese symbol that means "Family."
等等 我电脑上有
Wait, it's on my laptop.
你居然叫我来看这些东西
I can't believe you brought me in to do this!
就在这 就在这里
It's here, it's here.
这是我父亲的实验室
This is my father's lab.
这个实验室
This is the same lab
就是他们的出生地
where these things were born
或是创造地 变异地
or created or mutated.
我不知道要怎么用术语说
Or, I don't know the terminology,
但是你看看这个视频
but will you please just look at what
听我说 这些都是有联系的
I'm showing you and listen to me. It's all connected.
这些乌龟就是正义卫士
The turtles are the vigilantes
正义卫士就是这些乌龟
and the vigilantes are these turtles.
披萨上面有奶酪
Pizza has cheese,
番茄酱 都是你们喜欢的
tomato sauce, all your favorite stuff.
吃了吧 你们需要营养 也许不需要吧
Eat it. You guys need nutrition. Or not.
我只是想弄清楚
I just want to be clear.
你是在跟我说
You are now telling me that there are
有四只1米83的会说话乌龟穿梭在纽约城内
four six-foot talking turtles walking around New York city,
可除了你 没人看到过他们
and no one has seen them but you?
这就是我想说的
That's what I'm telling you.
我不是故意想笑
I don't mean to laugh,
你还有什么相关信息要告诉我吗
but is there anything else we should know about them?
他们是忍者
They're ninjas.
不好意思 什么
I'm sorry, what?
他们还会空手道
And they do karate.
你可以走了
Okay, get out.
奥尼尔
O'Neil!
其实也没有很糟
It could have been worse.
我刚刚被解雇 弗恩 怎么能不糟
I just got fired, Vern. How could it be worse?
也许是好事呢 也许你可以放个假
Maybe it's good. Maybe you should take a little time,
好好照顾自己
take care of yourself.
来吧 我来捎你一段路
Come on, let me give you a ride.
除非你要去埃里克·赛克斯庄园
Not unless you're going to the Eric Sacks estate.
- 爱普莉尔 - 我是不会放弃这个报道的
- April... Hey! - I'm not giving up on this story.
你还是放弃吧
You gotta put that to bed.
你合作过的其他优秀记者
Would all of those other great reporters
也会放弃自己的报道吗
that you worked with, would they have "Put it to bed"?
这不一样
No. That's different.
哪里不一样了
How is it different?
他们都是从我这样开始的 不是吗
They all started exactly where I am, right?
我不能开着第六频道的车去埃里克·赛克斯庄园
I'm not driving the Channel 6 news van onto the Sacks estate.
- 谁让你去了 - 你啊
- Who asked you to do that? - Uh, you did.
其实你只要说声谢谢就好
And a "Thanks" would have been nice.
也许有一天 你会感谢我呢
Maybe one day you're gonna be thanking me.
你为什么要找埃里克·赛克斯
So, what do you want with Eric Sacks?
我爸爸曾为他工作
My dad used to work for him.
只有他能够告诉我
He's the only person that's gonna be able
我是不是真的太疯狂
to tell me whether or not I'm crazy.
什么疯狂
Crazy about what?
笑话我的人已经够多了
I don't need you to laugh at me also.
不会的 奥尼尔
Oh, come on, O'Neil.
这可是芬威克专车
This is the Fenwick Express,
这里言论自由 是你绝对放心的小窝
it's a judgment-free zone. A cocoon of safety.
保证吗
Promise?
你居然会怀疑我 我受伤了
I'm insulted that you would suggest otherwise.
在边端待了十一个小时
Ooh, 11 hours in the Ha'shi.
真的没有人愿意告诉我
Are you sure none of you want to tell me
你们昨晚去了哪里吗
where you were last night?
坚持得怎么样 伙计们
How you holding up, fellas?
多尼能撑住 我就能撑住
I ain't breaking if Donnie ain't breaking.
我好想吐 不过我能撑住
Experiencing intense nausea but not breaking.
大伙 我进状态了
Guys? I'm in the zone!
现在的我绝对是无懈可击 坚如磐石
There is literally nothing that could break me right now!
要坚持不住了
Starting to break.
当然 你们都尝过五层芝士披萨
Of course, you've all tasted the five-cheese pizza.
但这个
But this,
乳酪商们花了几个世纪
cheesemongers have speculated
一直在探索它的奥妙
of its existence for centuries.
达芬奇的原创经典
Da Vinci's original masterpiece.
请欣赏…
I submit to you...
九九芝士披萨
...the 99-cheese pizza.
这简直不现实
It's not possible.
麦奇 这是个陷阱
Mikey, it's a trap!
一张披萨上根本放不了那么多芝士
A pizza with that variety of cheese is a culinary impossibility!
- 要我列一下具体的成分吗 - 不
- Shall I list the ingredients? - No.
干酪
Cheddar...
- 波萝伏洛干酪 - 麦奇 不要
- Provolone... - Mikey, don't you do it!
艾斯阿格芝士
Asiago...
坚持住
Keep it together!
软奶酪
Taleggio...
我甚至都不知道那是什么
I don't even know what that is.
当然还有 马苏里拉奶酪
Mozzarella, of course.
好吧 我招了 我们昨天出去是因为
All right, all right, all right! We left the lair
大脚帮在绑架人质
because the Foot were taking hostages
我们收拾了他们
and we kicked some serious butt,
后来出现了一个叫爱普莉尔·奥尼尔的女孩
and there was this girl named April O'Neil
她拍了我们的照片
who took our picture,
但是我们都处理好了
but we took care of it.
愚蠢
Idiot.
我最担心的事情终于来了
Oh, no, my worst fears have been realized.
别担心 多尼删了那些照片
Don't worry about it. Donnie erased the picture!
我们并没有危险
We're not in danger.
不 爱普莉尔·奥尼尔会有危险
No. It's April O'Neil who is in danger!
找到那个女孩 把她带过来
Find the girl. Bring her here.
但是 老师 你说过不要
But, sensei, you said to not go...
找到那个女孩
Find the girl!
Find the girl.
我给汤普森说了这些 她就开除了我
That's what I told Thompson and she fired me.
他们是外星人吗
So they're aliens?
不 怎么可能
No, that's stupid.
他们是爬行动物
They're reptiles.
他们帮助人们 我猜的
They help people, I guess.
龟壳中的英雄
Heroes in the half-shell.
- 好吧 - 也没那么疯狂
- Okay. - Come on. It's not that crazy.
我 动物王国充满了…
I... The animal kingdom is full of...
我曾养过一只会太空步的狗
I used to have a dog that could moonwalk.
多谢你送我 弗恩
Thanks for the ride, Vern.
没什么
Yeah. No problem.
最"棒"的感觉
Nothing better than
就是把一位美女送到一个有钱男人家里
dropping off a pretty girl at a rich guy's house.
我是爱普莉尔·奥尼尔 来见埃里克·赛克斯
Hi, it's April O'Neil, here to see Eric Sacks.
爱普莉尔今年来得比较早啊
April's arrived early this year.
很抱歉就这么闯了进来 赛克斯先生
I'm sorry to barge in on you like this, Mr. Sacks.
不 完全没有 请进
No, no, no. Please, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
我正在研究一个报道
I've been working on a story.
初步理论是 有一些正义卫士
And I have this theory that there are these vigilantes
在与大脚帮作斗争
that are fighting back against the Foot.
我觉得是你和我父亲创造了他们
I think you and my father may have created them.
我好像…
I'm not sure I...
能不能请您告诉我
Can you please tell me everything
关于文艺复兴项目的所有信息
that you know about Project Renaissance?
这么说吧 那曾是一个梦想
Well, um, it was a dream.
那个梦想和你父亲一起逝去了
A dream that died with your father.
如果它没有逝去呢
What if it isn't dead?
那不可能
That's impossible.
因为那场大火 我们失去了所有研究
We lost all our research in the fire,
我们的试验品 一切都没了
all our specimens, everything.
我花了15年的时间
I've spent the last 15 years
试图重制出当年的成果
trying to replicate the results.
那场大火并没有吞噬所有
You didn't lose everything in the fire.
这不可能
This can't be real.
这是真的
It is real.
我见到了他们四个
I saw all four of them.
你真的想了解文艺复兴项目吗
Do you really want to know about Project Renaissance?
- 是的 - 跟我来
- Yes. - Come with me.
我在日本出生 在冲绳的一个军事基地
I was born in Japan, at a military base in Okinawa.
我的父亲去了越南
My father went to Vietnam.
之后并没有回来
Didn't come back.
我孤身一人在异国他乡
I was an outsider in a foreign land.
被当成怪物
A freak.
当时的我脆弱而无助
I was a powerless and helpless boy.
直到一个当地老师收我为徒
Until a local sensei took me under his wing.
他救了我
And he saved me.
教了我很多知识 之后我也跟你父亲分享了
Taught me lessons that I later shared with your father.
十九世纪的日本
Ninth-century Japan.
一个邪恶的军阀控制着那片土地
An evil warlord ruled the land.
他在供水系统里下了毒 开启了黑暗时代
He poisoned the water supply, bringing on the dark ages.
死亡和疾病肆意猖獗 哀横遍野
Death and disease and suffering ran rampant.
就像大脚帮
Not unlike the Foot Clan
他们也想毁掉我们的城市
and what they'd like to do to our city.
之后有一天 出现了一个英雄
Then one day, a hero arose.
一个伟大的炼金术士研究出了解药
A great alchemist discovered the antidote
解了军阀所下的毒
to the warlord's poison.
针对邪恶的
The cure-all
万灵药
for his evil.
我和你父亲就是在试图创造这个万灵药
Your father and I were trying to recreate that cure-all.
我们开发了一种变异原
We developed a mutagen
可以在细胞层级
capable of stimulating self-repair
激发自我修复功能
on a cellular level.
你们准备用它干什么
What were you going to do with it?
如果纽约
Imagine New York City,
遭到某种化学攻击
being victim to a chemical attack.
这种变异原可以抵挡住这种影响
This mutagen would be able to reverse its effects.
它可以拯救城市 可以拯救人民
It would save the city, it would save the people.
那些实验对象 那些乌龟们
Those test subjects, those turtles...
他们血液里的
Running in their blood
就是最后的珍贵变异原
is the last of this precious mutagen.
要不是你刚刚告诉我
And up until a few moments ago,
我还以为我们失败了
I thought we failed.
我以为他们死在了大火里 怎么
I thought they died in the fire. How...
他们是怎么活下来的
How could they have lived?
因为我救了他们
Because I saved them.
当然是你
Of course you did.
爱普莉尔 那些变异原
April, the mutagen possesses powers
有着我们无法企及的力量
beyond our wildest hopes.
无论你需要什么资源
Whatever resources you need,
欢迎找我
I'm here.
我们一起努力 会找到他们的
Let's work together. We'll find them.
(赛克斯)
人类历史的进程可能会因此改变
The course of human history may depend on it.
我送你出去
I'll show you out.
(纽约的正义卫士)
(纽约 地铁正义卫士)
你的电脑被我黑了
Bam! You've been hacked!
我是多纳泰罗 还记得我吗
By Donatello. Remember me?
乌龟 四眼 不说我了
Turtle. Four eyes. But enough about me.
我们说过会去找你 来这里见我们
We told you we'd find you. Meet us here.
一个人来 否则 否则我们…
And come alone. Or... Or else we're...
你会遭到惩罚 什么的
You shall be punished and stuff.
有人吗
Hello?
你们让我来这里的
You told me to come here.
我并没有带任何人
I didn't bring anyone with me.
我的确…
I did exactly...
好的 你是爱普莉尔·奥尼尔吗
Okay! Are you April O'Neil?
启动视网膜扫描
Initiating retinal scan.
扫描 扫描 扫描 扫描
Scanning, scanning, scanning, scanning.
扫描结束 是她 大伙 就是她
Scan complete. It's her. It's her. Guys, it's her!
当然是她了 多尼
Of course it's her, Donnie.
你好 很开心你能来
Hey. Really glad you could make it.
我们想给你介绍一位
Hey. There's someone important
很重要的人 不过在此之前
we want to introduce you to, but first...
太棒了 欢迎来到我们的小屋
Aw, yeah, welcome to my crib, girl.
这是哪里
Where are we?
这是我们的孤独堡垒
Hey, it's our Fortress of Solitude.
我们的霍格沃茨
Our Hogwarts.
我们的泽维尔学院
Our Xavier Academy.
最先进的奇妙世界
State-of-the-art WonderDome!
这是在下水道里面吗
Are we in the sewer?
不
No.
- 其实是的 - 是的
- Technically, yes. - Yeah.
没错 就是下水道
Yeah, it's a sewer.
是你把我们带到这里来的 爱普莉尔
You brought us here, April.
斯普林特
Splinter?
她怎么知道他的名字的
How does she know his name?
是你告诉她的吗
Did you tell her his name?
也许她是千里眼
Maybe she's clairvoyant.
也许她是绝地武士呢
Maybe she's a Jedi!
过来
Come closer.
很久不见了
It's been a long time.
你确实有双和你父亲一样的眼睛
You always did have your father's eyes.
我不懂
I don't understand.
别害怕 我会告诉你一切的
Don't be afraid. All will be made clear.
这简直太疯狂了
This is crazy.
[日语] 你来干什么
[日语] 学生
有奇迹出现了
There's been a miracle.
那些一直妨碍我们的义务警员
The vigilantes who've been causing us so much trouble?
他们是实验对象
They're the test subjects.
我们以为死在大火里的
Those itty-bitty box turtles
那些小箱龟
that we thought we lost in the fire?
他们还活着 施莱德大师
They're alive, Master Shredder.
不仅如此 他们还成长得
And they've grown into something
十分强大
powerful.
抓住他们不是易事 但一旦我们成功了
It won't be easy to capture them, but if we can,
我们就能实现
we can finally carry out the plan
多年前一直筹备的计划了
that we had all those years ago.
[日语] 我的大脚帮会更强大 而你将富可敌国
这座城市会成为我们掌中之物
The city will be ours.
[日语] 找到他们
是奥尼尔的女儿找到了他们
O'Neil's daughter was the one who found them
她会带领我们找到他们
and she will be the one who will take us right to them.
有脉冲信号了
There's the ping.
我们已经突破了他们的隐身安全系统
We've breached the cloaking security.
听我说 爱普莉尔
Listen closely, April.
我已经不记得
I don't remember a time
去那实验室之前的生活了
before living in that laboratory.
那宿命的一夜同往常一样
That fateful night started like any other.
赛克斯给我们进行了注射
Sacks gave us our injections.
你的父亲保证我们的生命体征依然强健
Your father made sure our vital signs were strong.
而你 一如往常
And you, as always,
给我们带来了小奖励
provided us with a special treat.
在兄弟们睡着之后
After the brothers went to sleep,
我听到了很大的声响
I heard loud voices.
在那里面
In there.
我闻到了烟味
There was the smell of smoke.
警铃响起
Alarms sounded.
你父亲发现了他的老板
Your father had discovered the truth
做实验的真实企图
behind the man he was working for.
他放火烧了实验室
He set fire to the lab.
努力摧毁施莱德的计划
His last breath was taken
也咽下了最后一口气
trying to destroy Shredder's plan.
我吓坏了
I was terrified.
但就在那时 你出现了
But then, you appeared.
把我们带到了安全的地方
And ushered us to safety.
我当时无法说话
I never had a voice then,
但我现在想谢谢你 爱普莉尔
but I thank you now, April.
我们一直在下水道里游荡直到我找到了这里
We wandered the sewers until I found this place.
就在那时
It was then that the mutagen
我们血液中的变异原
that was injected into our blood
奇迹般地改造了我们
began to change us in miraculous ways.
我目睹过你父亲对你的爱
I saw how your father loved you
我知道我必须对神龟们施以同样的爱
and I knew I had to show that same love to the turtles.
我成为了他们的父亲
I became their father
而他们则成为了我的儿子
and they became my sons.
同所有的孩子一样
Like all children, they were drawn
他们也被流行文化吸引
to the distractions of popular culture.
我知道总有一天他们会去探索地面之上的世界
I knew one day they would want to explore the world above.
他们会被嘲笑
They would be ridiculed.
他们得学会如何保护自己
They would need to learn to protect themselves,
不管是身体还是心理
both mentally and physically.
有人想玩"打小桶"吗
Hey. Does anyone want to play Buck-Buck?
一个桶
Buck one!
两个桶
Buck two!
三个桶
Buck three!
你要去哪儿 拉斐
Where you going, Raph?
别这样 我一个人做不来
Come on. I can't do it by myself.
得四个人一起才行
I need all four!
你是桶渣
You're a Buck short.
听起来好蠢 就和你一样 麦奇
Yeah, that sounds stupid. Like you, Mikey!
所以你只负责搞热气氛嘛 兄弟
That's why you're just the hype man, bra.
- 看见这些动作了吗 - 我才不管呢
- See these moves? - Yeah, whatever, man.
(忍术)
后来我找到了一种方法
And then I found a way.
首先 我自学这种古老的忍术
First, I would teach myself the ancient art of Ninjutsu.
小龟们则跟随我的指导
The brothers followed my lead,
他们以飞一般地速度成长起来
accelerating at a wondrous rate!
怎么样 兄弟 要来试试吗
Wassup, bra? Want some of this?
我就像幽灵
I'm like a ghost!
我在这里 我又在这里 就像一道暗影
I'm over here, now I'm over here, bra. Like a shadow!
我就是火焰暗影龙
I'm a flame shadow fire dragon!
他们的天赋正是他们的热情所在
Their gift was also their passion.
他们活着 呼吸着 并梦想着
They lived, breathed and dreamed
和武术相关的一切
all things martial arts.
就这样
Then,
他们准备好了
they were ready.
武士刀 所有刀刃中最高贵的
The katana, most noble of all the blades.
领袖所用的武器
It is the weapon of a leader.
他们的现在
Everything they are,
以及他们的未来
and everything that they've become
都离不开你在那宿命的一夜
was made possible by the bravery that
所展现出的勇敢
you displayed on that fateful night.
老兄
Dude.
我那时只是个小女孩
I was just a little girl.
别人可能会把我们关起来
And you gave us freedom
你却赐予了我们自由
where others would have kept us in cages.
等等 爸爸
Wait a minute, Dad.
这些年来你一直告诉我们 在那场大火中
All these years you told us we were rescued from the fire
一个叫作保护者的守护神救了我们
by a great guardian spirit, the Hogo-sha.
正是如此
That's right.
她就是那位保护者
And this is the Hogo-sha.
你说什么
What?
我女朋友就是保护者啊
My girlfriend's totally the Hogo-sha.
幸运的是 我们的工程师
Fortunately, our engineers
对您盔甲的机械技术
have been making great progress
做了很大的改进
in refining the robotics in your armor.
我们提升了它的层次
We're taking it to the next level,
结合了古代传统
bridging the gap between ancient tradition
和现代战术
and modern warfare.
[日语] 今晚 我要喝乌龟汤
你为什么把我带到这里来
Why did you bring me here?
我想要知道你把我们的存在告诉了谁
To find out who you told of our existence.
除了埃里克·赛克斯 没人相信我
Nobody that believed me, except for Eric Sacks.
赛克斯
Sacks.
真是怕什么来什么
Just as I feared.
赛克斯不是善类
Sacks is not a friend.
他的心灵已被荼毒
His soul has been poisoned
荼毒他的是暗夜帝王
by the influence of a dark master.
施莱德
The Shredder.
施莱德在日本把赛克斯抚养成人
Shredder practically raised Sacks in Japan.
他就像是赛克斯的父亲
He's like a father to him.
为了主人 赛克斯什么都愿意做
Sacks will do anything for his master.
等等 等等
Wait, wait.
赛克斯和施莱德
Sacks and Shredder?
那我们为什么不出去抓他们呢
So, why aren't we out there hunting them down?
拉斐尔 那是因为
Because, Raphael,
施莱德是有史以来最残忍的战士
The Shredder is a skilled warrior
并且 他战斗技术娴熟
whose cruelty is ever-reaching!
而你们不过是一群少年
And you are just teenagers.
你们血液中的变异原对他们很有价值
The mutagen in your blood is of great value to them.
现在赛克斯已经确信
Now that Sacks has confirmation
你们还活着
that you are alive,
恐怕他们会来找我们
I fear they will bring the fight to us.
不
Oh, no.
准备进入 行动
Stand by to make entry. Let's move!
快 快
Go, go, go!
有人入侵 已经侵入 有人来了
Perimeter infringe. Breached! We have incoming!
不 不 有两队人马侵入
Oh, no! Oh, no! We got two breaches.
通风机室和武器墙
Fan room, weapons wall!
麦奇 从右侧包抄 多尼跟我来
Mikey, flank right! Donnie, on me!
我们得出发了 快
We gotta go! Go, go!
准备装载炸药
Stand by to set charge.
子弹上膛 10秒后突进
Lock and load. We're going on 10.
别用实弹 只准用麻醉弹
No live ammo. Tranqs only.
活捉他们
Take 'em alive!
不 后退
No! Get back!
多尼
Donnie!
进攻
Engage!
抓住他
Get him!
他们在那里 麻醉他们
There they are! Neutralize them!
他们有麻醉弹
They've got tranq darts!
那就别碰到那子弹
Well, don't let them hit your skin.
上啊 上啊
Let's go! Let's move!
在那里
Over there!
目标在正前方
Tango at 12!
干嘛 兄弟 你觉得你能搞定这个吗
Wassup, bra? Oh, you think you can handle this, huh?
我行如闪电 蠢货们 我闪我闪我闪
I'm a snapping turtle, fool. Snap, snap, snap!
我故意的 我故意的
I meant to do that! I meant to do it!
通风机室有人侵入
We got a breach in the fan room!
拉斐 去通风机室
Raph! Get to the fan room!
凭什么你老使唤我
Why are you always telling me what to do?
快去 麦奇 你得把爱普莉尔带出去 快
Just go! Mikey, you gotta get April out of here, now!
没问题
I got this!
爱普莉尔 跟我来
April, come with me.
我知道你在哪儿藏着最安全
I got a safe place for you to hide.
如果你口渴的话
And if you get thirsty,
我在冰箱后偷藏了橙子汽水
I got a secret stash of Orange Crush behind the fridge.
别告诉拉斐
Don't tell Raph.
施莱德
Shredder.
这么多年来
All these years
我一直想重造那个变异原
I've been trying to recreate the mutagen.
而你
And you?
真是得来全不费工夫
You just handed it to me.
你休想伤害我的儿子们
You will not lay a hand on my sons.
你儿子
Your sons?
你竟然觉得你是他们的父亲吗
You think you're their father?
不错啊 小老鼠
Very good, rat!
老师
Sensei!
多尼
Donnie!
坚持住 李奥 我马上就来
Hang on, Leo! Be right there!
你这个蠢货
You stupid little girl!
爱普莉尔
April!
老师
Sensei!
不 儿子 别过来
No, my son, stay back!
老师
Sensei!
老师 爸爸
Sensei! Dad!
爸爸 你在 你要做什么
Dad! What are you... What are you doing?
藏起来
Hide!
不
No!
保护好自己
Save yourselves!
孩子们 放下武器
Children, drop your weapons,
否则 你们的父亲必死无疑
or your father will die.
不
No!
还有一个呢
Where's the fourth?
他死了
He's dead.
毁了这里
Destroy this place.
继续走
Keep moving!
要坚强
Stay strong.
记住 痛苦只是大脑的信号
Remember, pain's only in the mind.
进去 快
Move along! Go!
军队 出发
Troop, go!
快走 快走
Move! Move!
斯普林特
Splinter.
老师
Sensei.
大师
Master.
送他去医疗室吧
Let's get him to the needle room.
货物安全 已经上路
Package is secured. En route.
带来了三只乌龟 大概40分钟后到
We are carrying 3 specimens and will be arriving at the estate in approximately 40 minutes.
准备好密封间
Prepare the containment units.
这些乌龟的身体里
Inside those turtles
有地球上最珍贵的化合物
is the most precious compound on Earth,
变异原
mutagen.
为了得到变异原
And we will drain every last
我们要榨干他们的最后一滴血
ounce of their blood to get it,
杀了他们也在所不惜
even if it kills them.
去拿急救箱 就在架子上
Get the first aid kit! On the shelf!
快点 快点
Hurry. Hurry.
拉斐尔
Raphael?
我在
I'm here.
你一定要救出你的兄弟们
You must save your brothers.
阻止施莱德
Stop Shredder.
老师
Sensei.
好像是某种跟踪装置
It's some kind of tracker.
是多纳泰罗
It's Donatello!
快去 拉斐尔
Go, Raphael.
我们去救我的兄弟吧
Let's go save my brothers.
我们需要搭便车
We need a ride.
奥尼尔
O'Neil!
听着 弗恩 10分钟后
Look, Vern, I need you to meet me
在柯特兰小路见 拜托了
at Cortlandt Alley in 10 minutes, please.
等等 为什么
Wait, why?
在电话里说不清
I can't talk to you about it on the phone.
答应我 你一定要去
Just promise you're gonna be there.
什么叫说不清 电话是你打给…
What do you mean, you can't talk about... You called...
我的
me.
好吧 要我现在就去见你对吧
All right. Want me to meet you right now?
我就配合你好了
I'll play your little game.
这帽子是怎么回事
What's with the hat?
这帽子
What is with the...
不知道 这是我朋友的 我失策了
I don't know, it's a buddy of mine's. It's just a goof.
你想干点什么 去市中心如何
What do you want to do? You wanna head downtown?
埃里克·赛克斯在为大脚帮首领工作
Eric Sacks is working with the head of the Foot Clan.
他们把正义乌龟卫士抓住了
They just kidnapped the vigilante turtles
要把他们带到赛克斯府邸去
to take them to the Sacks estate.
我们得过去 快点 弗恩
We need to go. Come on, Vern.
好 好 好 乌龟 我忘了
Right, right, right. The turtles. I forgot.
这有些为难我了 奥尼尔
This is getting embarrassing. O'Neil,
我们都是成年人
we're both consenting adults.
长得都挺不错
We're both very good-looking.
也许你更好看些
You're better, probably.
这一点待议
That's up for debate.
但问题是 我们不需要找借口
But the point is, we don't need to make up excuses
- 才能跟彼此见面 - 你说什么
- to hang out with each other. - What?
你想多跟我待在一起
You want to spend more time with me.
我明白 我也想
I get it. I would too.
我们现在就得去赛克斯府邸 弗恩
We need to get to the Sacks estate right now, Vern.
- 快点 - 我就是说这个问题
- Come on! - That's what I'm talking about,
什么赛克斯府邸和正义卫士
the Sacks estate with the vigilante...
快开
Drive!
你是个会说话的乌龟
You're a talking turtle.
是 我是个会说话的乌龟
Yeah. Yeah, I'm a talking turtle,
你是个呆子人类
and you're a human nerd.
既然理清楚身份了 踩油门吧
Now that we got that out of the way, hit it.
从来没人说我是呆子…
I've never been accused of being a nerd before, but...
请问一下…
I'm sorry...
你是怎么进到…
How did you get in...
他是怎么进到…
How did he get in the...
天啊
Oh, my.
难以置信 让我好好看看你们
Unbelievable. Let me look at you.
虽然我见多识广 可这…
I'm a hard guy to impress, but...
可这也…
This is just...
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们本来还想用兔子呢
And we were gonna use rabbits!
能想象吗
Can you imagine that?
我们本来就想创造一种解药
All we were trying to do is create an antidote.
为了什么
For what?
再说一遍 我想听你的声音
Say that again. I want to hear your voice.
为了什么
For what?
我们有这么一个计划
Well, uh, we had this plan.
我们准备今天重新实施
A plan that we're ready to put back online today.
我会给你们展示的 卡莱
I'll show you. Karai.
让他们瞧瞧
Show them.
动手
やれ
干什么
What?
知道我的赛克斯之塔吗
Do you know my building, Sacks Tower?
最高处有个巨型尖顶的那个
Got that great big spire up on top?
那个尖顶里充满了…
That spire is filled...
成吨的化学毒气
with tons of chemical toxins.
别 别
No! No!
如你们所见
Bad stuff.
这东西很不好
That kinda bad.
再过几小时
In a few hours,
施莱德就会把那些东西
Shredder is going to unleash all that stuff
洒满整个城市
over the whole city.
初期死亡人数
The initial death toll
绝对会让世界各政府为之震惊
will shake world governments to their core.
三十天之内
In 30 days,
纽约城会成为隔离区
the city of New York will be a quarantine zone.
这时我的公司就会出面
And that is where my company comes in.
我会拿出解药
I'm going to save everyone
拯救大家 而解药的来源
with the antidote that is made from the mutagen
就是你们血中流淌着的变异原
that is oozing through your blood.
政府会给赛克斯企业
The government will then send Sacks Industry
一张无限额支票 我会变得富有
a blank check and I'm going to be rich.
富得一塌糊涂
Like, stupid rich.
施莱德会驱使这座城市臣服于我们
Shredder will force this city to live under our rule.
我们将成为神
We will be gods.
我有考虑过…
Yeah, I've thought about...
倒不是说要当忍者
not becoming a ninja,
不过我练过一阵子瑜伽
but I was doing a bunch of yoga for like,
一度练了十天
10 days at one point,
后来拉伤了小腿
and, uh, I pulled a hamstring.
- 大门在那 - 我们到了
- There's the gate right there. - There it is.
把门撞开
Ram the gate.
把门撞开 这车可是归第六频道所有
"Ram the gate"? This is Channel 6 property.
我叫你把门撞开
I said ram the gate!
好吧 两位 抓稳了
All right, everybody, strap in!
糟了
Oh, shit!
走 走 走
Go, go, go, go!
跟我来
Follow me!
我把这罐拿到纽约
I'll take this canister to New York
提取变异原
to withdraw the mutagen.
一定要把他们的血抽干
Make sure that you drain all their blood.
是时候吞食大苹果(纽约的爱称)了
Time to take a bite out of the Big Apple.
快出去
Hey! Get out of here!
李奥
Leo!
终于来了
About time.
搞什么…
What the...
拉斐尔
Raphael.
欢迎加入我们
Glad you could join us.
第四个笼子是为你准备的
The fourth cage is for you.
摔得真惨 哥们儿
That's harsh, man.
老鼠没把你教好
The rat did not teach you well!
拉斐尔
Raphael!
是你
You.
你的对手是我
Focus on me.
三只… 总共四只乌龟
Three... four total turtles.
有一只在和机械武士打架
One's fighting a robot samurai.
挺好的
Why not?
多尼
Donnie!
我该怎么办
What I do?
- 肾上腺素 - 什么
- Adrenaline. - What?
肾上腺素
Adrenaline.
好的 好的
All right. All right.
(注射肾上腺素)
肾上腺素
Adrenaline.
他要杀了他
He's going to kill him.
(警告 已使用肾上腺素 即将过量)
快起来
Get up!
起效了
It's working.
我觉得咱们得让开点
I think we should move.
现在感觉真棒
I feel really good right now!
好想跑步
I feel like running!
好想打扫卫生
I feel like cleaning!
谁想打扫道场
Who wants to clean the dojo?
我来打扫道场
I'll clean the dojo!
内啡肽 内啡肽
Endorphins! Endorphins!
我们得去找拉斐
We got to get Raph!
拉斐 拉斐
Raph! Raph!
你还好吗 你死了吗
Are you okay? Are you dead?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
- 去哪 - 赛克斯之塔
- Go where? - Sacks Tower!
纽约城 时代广场
New York City! Times Square!
施莱德要释放毒气
Shredder's going to release a toxin!
毒害整座城市
It's gonna poison the whole city!
然后赛克斯会卖解药
And Sacks is gonna sell the antidote!
解药由变异原制成
Made from the mutagen.
变异原从我们血里提取
That's in our blood!
我们现在就得行动起来
So we've got to get going now!
好 让我们为师父一战
Good. Let's do it for sensei.
好 我们走
Okay. We're going!
大家都淡定
Everybody calm down!
看我多淡定
Look how calm I am!
要行动了 快走
We got to move. Let's go!
赛克斯坐飞机走了
Sacks is airborne!
飞到曼哈顿要十九分钟
Flight time to Manhattan, 19 minutes!
领我们走 多尼
Get us out of here, Donnie!
天啊 他们有枪
Oh, my gosh, they have guns!
蹲下 蹲下
Get down! Get down!
你们没事吧
Are you guys okay?
我们是防弹的
We're bulletproof.
爽歪歪
Sweet!
前进 开火
Advance and engage!
你能开那辆货车吗
Can you drive that truck?
能
Yeah!
拉斐来掩护 准备好了吗
We're on Raph. Ready?
快来
Come on!
大家快进货车
Everybody in the truck!
走 走 走 快走
We gotta go, go, go! Move!
弗恩 你会开这辆车吧
Vern, you know how to drive this, right?
会 我猜得先把车打着火
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just got to hotwire this thing, I guess.
经典蓝红线设定
Classic blue wire/red wire situation.
- 有钥匙 - 好的
- Keys! - Yeah.
钥匙更好用
Keys are better.
- 开车 - 遵命
- Drive! - I'm on it!
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
后座上有个会说话的乌龟也是醉了
That's all I need is a backseat-driving talking turtle!
- 快走 - 行动
- Let's go! - Move!
十二点方向
Jackal-One-Tango, on your 12!
收到
Copy that.
我不该怀疑你的
I shouldn't have doubted you.
很抱歉我之前没信你
Sorry I didn't stick up for you.
真不敢相信你居然没疯
I can't believe that you're not crazy!
这真是太疯狂了
How crazy is that?
目标 十二点方向
Target, 12 o'clock!
我们要去哪 伙计们
Where are we going, guys?
多尼 去曼哈顿最快是哪条路
Donnie, what's the fastest way back to Manhattan?
只要在这条路上开就好了
We just need to stay on this road.
如果我们能到山脚下的维修舱
If we can get to the maintenance hatch at the bottom of the hill,
那里有条四公里的下水管道
there's a sewer line 2.4 miles from here.
麦奇 告诉前面那两个
Mikey! Let them know up there!
交给我了
I'm on it!
不要啊
Oh, no.
弗恩 走 走 走 走
Vern, go, go, go, go, go!
没问题
I'm on it!
停车
Stop!
弗恩 踩刹车
Vern, hit the brakes!
反了 反了
Wrong way! Wrong way!
快追 快 快
Go around! Go, go, go!
- 李奥 快让开 - 什么
- Leo, move, move! - What?
转过来 转过来 转过来
Opposite, opposite, opposite!
不
Oh, no!
我们偏离了路线多少
How far off course are we?
其实我们现在走上了捷径
Actually, we're on a bit of a shortcut.
可我们得一直开下去
But we need to keep going down.
一直往下开
Straight down.
一直
Just keep
往下开
going straight!
还好吗 美人儿
What's up, angel cakes?
开火
Fire!
伙计们 李奥有麻烦了
Guys, Leo's in trouble!
我的壳裂了
My shell's cracked.
随便粘起来就行
Just tape it up.
就让我出次风头吧
Allow me to be the bad-ass for once.
挺住了 李奥 解除
Hang on, Leo. Disengaging.
老天 我一直想试试这招
God, I've always wanted to try this.
有我在 兄弟
I got you, brother.
搞定一辆 还有两辆
One car down, two to go.
麦奇
Mikey!
好吧 够了
All right, that's it.
接下来交给我吧
I'll take it from here!
拉斐 我在开车诶
Raph, I'm driving! Yeah!
奥尼尔 你在干什么
O'Neil, what are you doing?
没事 你继续
Yeah, that's good.
一定要都拍下来
Make sure you're getting everything.
弗恩
Vern!
奥尼尔 把胳膊给我
O'Neil! Give me your arm!
弗恩
Vern!
雪崩
Avalanche!
快点 李奥 快醒过来
Come on, Leo, wake up!
如果你醒过来
Yeah! If you wake up,
我保证乖乖听话
I promise to do anything you say!
伙计们 施莱德的直升机离纽约
Guys! Shredder's chopper is 20 miles
还有三十二公里
outside of New York City airspace!
感谢播报交通情况 多尼
Thanks for the traffic update, Donnie.
接下来要播体育和天气吗
You doing sports and weather next?
如果你现在就这么生气
If you're gonna be nasty about it
我猜你肯定不想知道
then I guess you don't want to know
53秒后会有150米落差
that there's a 500-foot drop-off in 53 seconds!
你是说…
Are you saying there's...
有悬崖
A cliff!
我们得把爱普莉尔救出来
We gotta get April out of there!
拉斐 注意
Raph, heads up!
别忘了那个老头儿
Don't forget that old guy!
计划有变
Hi. Change of plans.
别啊
Oh, come on.
低头 低头
Guys, get down! Get down!
还有20秒我们就完了
Twelve seconds and we're going over!
多尼 用弹弓那招
Hey, Donnie, do that fancy slingshot thing!
我们得把阳光小姐救出来
We got to take Little Miss Sunshine out!
击球员就位
Batter up!
抓稳
Grab on.
麦奇 抓住钢缆
Mikey! Grab the cable!
抓住了 抓住了
I got it! I got it!
坚持住 坚持住
Hold on! Hold on!
不
Oh, no!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
不
Oh, no...
可怜的李奥 爱普莉尔…
Poor Leo, April...
还有那个家伙
and that other guy.
他们那么年轻 那么漂亮
They were so young, so beautiful.
他们没死 笨蛋
They ain't dead, dumb nuts.
来咯
Oh. Right on.
我希望你的龟壳下面有降落伞
I hope you got a parachute under that shell.
伙计们 是维修舱
Hey, guys! It's the maintenance hatch!
可以回家了
Our ticket home!
先帮我一把好吗
A little help, please!
各位 我们得赶紧了
Guys, we gotta hustle.
施莱德已经到纽约市了
Shredder's over New York City!
老师 变异原还有四分钟就好了
Sensei, the mutagen is four minutes out.
按照计划前进
Moving forward as planned.
记住不要把胳膊腿
Please keep your arms and legs
伸出龟壳外哦
inside the shell at all times.
卫星图像显示
Satellite imagery shows
施莱德已经到达赛克斯塔塔顶了
Shredder's reached the top of Sacks Tower.
如果他从那里释放毒素…
If that's where he's releasing the toxin from...
那整个纽约就要完了
It's gonna spread all over the city!
我们需要…
We need to...
左拐
...break a left!
好 大家听好
All right, listen up.
我们得找到电梯 坐电梯上塔顶
We gotta find the elevators and get up to the roof.
你们去安全的地方
Get to a safe distance.
不不 我们可以去找赛克斯
No, no, we can go find Sacks
从他手里抢来变异原 作为应急方案
and get our hands on the mutagen as a contingency plan,
就是…以防万一
just in case... you know.
谢谢你这么"信任"我们
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
如果我们没回来
If we don't make it back,
你就把变异原带去给斯普林特
bring the mutagen to Splinter.
可以救他一命
It can save his life.
赛克斯的实验室在36楼
Sacks's laboratory's on the 36th floor.
我已经把安保系统禁用了
I've already disabled the security system.
对了…
Oh, and, uh...
祝大家好运
Good luck!
如果我不回来 不要忘记我 爱普莉尔
If I don't return, remember me, April.
我会一直
You can always find me
在这里
in here.
没想到你这么有"故事"
You're a complicated chick.
成功了
Yeah.
电梯就在拐角处
Elevator's just around this corner!
兄弟们 听我说
All right, guys, listen up.
按我的计划来 我们就不会失败
We stick to my plan and we won't fail.
大家散开 三 二 一
Fan out in three, two, one.
这里不是电梯
Not the elevator.
确实
Nope.
第一瓶解毒剂正在装瓶
The first vial is filling with antidote now.
启动毒剂释放程序
Initiating the toxin release procedure.
麦奇控麦
MC Mikey.
控麦
MC
准备出招
Ready, stance!
麦奇 还记得我们小时候
Hey, Mikey, remember that thing you used to say
你经常说的那句话吗
when we were kids?
你说不允许我再说了
You made me promise never to say it again.
别管那个了
Forget about that.
你还记得怎么说吗
Still got one in the tank?
我都蓄势待发好多年了
I've been holding it in for years.
兄弟们 我们得先定个计划
Guys, we need a plan!
考厄崩格
Cowabunga!
李奥
Leo!
这里发生交火
Yeah, we got a 10-10.
有碎片正从赛克斯大楼上落下
Debris falling from the building.
快点
Come on.
交给我 兄弟们 我来对付他
I got this, guys! I'll take him!
来吧
Come on!
你一个人可对付不了
Oh, no, you don't!
说真的
Seriously,
你们俩…
you two...
你们俩可真可爱
You're adorable, really.
可爱到我想捏捏你们的脸
I could just pinch your cheeks!
兄弟们 他过来了 他来了
Guys, he's coming, he's coming!
兄弟们
Guys!
多尼
Donnie!
抓住 坚持住
Come on, come on!
坚持住 李奥
Hold on, Leo!
一个小姑娘老想着死去的爸爸 这个我懂
I understand a girl with dead daddy issues.
真的 但你阻止不了我
I do. But you're not gonna stop me.
这真是历史重演啊
This is history repeating itself.
你父亲也阻止过我 爱普莉尔
Your father walked in on me, April,
就跟你一样
just like you did.
不过我没费这么多子弹就把他杀了
It took a few less bullets to take him down, though.
是你杀了我父亲
You killed my father.
(毒剂释放)
快上 快
Move! Move!
快点上
Go, go, go!
坚持 兄弟们
Come on, guys!
抓住你了
Got you!
行了 教训就到此为止
Enough. The lesson is over.
我们被他打得好惨啊
We're getting our asses kicked out there.
我们还有五十秒时间
We only got 50 more seconds
否则毒剂就要释放了
before the toxin's released.
我说
Hey.
谁想玩打小桶吗
Who wants to play Buck-Buck?
打小桶
Buck-Buck?
- 什么 - 打小桶 又叫骑小马
- What? - Buck-Buck. Tony-on-a-Pony.
也有人称之为垫石头
Some people call it Johnnie-on-a-Rock.
等等
Wait.
好
Yeah.
我们玩打小桶吧
Let's play Buck-Buck.
- 但是我们为什么… - 不
- But why would we... - No.
听李奥的话
We do what Leo says.
你先上
Lead the way.
奥尼尔
O'Neil!
考厄崩格
Cowabunga.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
快带上变异原去找人帮忙
Look, just go get some help and take the mutagen with you.
快去 快去啊
Just go. Go! No!
作为一名实干家 这一天很平常
Just another day in the life of a man of action.
不好 我起不来了
No, I'm not getting up.
你知道怎么用这玩意儿吗
You know how to use this thing?
这是个简单的命令运行界面
It's a simple command-line interface.
这种代码已经有15年没人用了
No one's used this code in 15 years.
我也只是在网上看到过
I mean, I've read about it online.
要弄明白这玩意儿需要时间
But these kind of things take time.
我没想过有一天纽约整个城市的命运
Thinking there was no way I'd ever be in a position
会掌握在我手上…
where the fate of an entire city...
我去给你争取时间
I'll buy you some time.
毒剂释放倒计时
Toxin disbursement
五 四
in five, four,
三
three,
二…
two...
耶 系统解除了
Bam! System disabled!
谁想吃意式披萨
Who wants Italian?
我请客
I'm buying!
免费请大家吃提拉米苏
Tiramisu for everybody!
塔要倒了
Fall in!
顶住
Hold on!
顶住 顶住
Hold it! Hold it!
如果尖塔倒塌毒剂跌落到地面
If the spire falls and the toxin makes ground impact,
污染范围会覆盖十个街区
it'll contaminate a 10-block radius!
我们能阻止这种情况发生的概率是多少
What are the odds of us stopping that from happening?
百分之零点零零零零零零零零零零三
Uh, 0.00000000003%!
我愿意冒这个险 无论如何谁都不准走开
I'll take it. Nobody moves, no matter what.
但是 李奥…
But, Leo...
我说了谁都不准走开
I said nobody moves!
李奥 我顶不住了
Leo, I'm letting go!
施莱德
Shredder!
变异原就剩这么多了
This is all that's left!
小姑娘
Little girl.
那是我的
That belongs to me.
顶住 顶住啊
Hold on! Hold on!
顶住
Hold it!
后退 大家都后退
Get back! All the way back!
爱普莉尔
April!
快来 兄弟们
Come on, guys!
爱普莉尔
April!
抓住你了 拉斐
Got you, Raph!
抓住
Hold on!
抓紧了 爱普莉尔
Hold on! April!
我抓住你了
I got you.
把我往他那边甩
Swing me towards him!
快
Do it!
李奥
Leo!
干得漂亮
That's my girl.
我们好像快死了 兄弟们
I think this is it, guys!
谁有什么话要说吗
Does anyone have anything they want to say?
多尼
Donnie?
是我每天早上
I'm the one who licks the icing
把馅饼上面的酥皮都舔了
off the Pop-Tarts every morning
然后再放回盒子里的
and puts them back in the box.
不不不不
No, no, no, no!
我真心不懂《迷失》的结局
I so did not understand the ending of Lost.
拉斐
Raph?
我…
I just,
如果这是我们在一起的最后一刻
if this is our last moment together,
我想跟大家说一声对不起
I just want you guys to know I'm sorry.
对不起我对你们那么严厉
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
每次我都逼你们 我…
Every time I pushed you, I...
我威胁你们 冲你们吼
I threatened you, I yelled at you,
我逼你们突破自己的极限
I pushed you beyond your limits,
那是因为我相信你们
it was because I believe in you!
我相信你们每个人
I believe in each one of you!
我相信你们的精神 相信你们的能力
I believe in your spirit and your intelligence
也相信你们的潜力
and your potential.
每次我说要走
And every time I talked about walking away,
那是因为我害怕
it was because I was scared!
我只是觉得我不够优秀
I just didn't think I was good enough
没资格站在你们身边
to stand next to you
叫你们兄弟 并且跟你们说
and call you brothers and say to you
我爱你们
I love you!
我真的很爱你们
I love you guys so much!
拉斐
Raph?
我们没死
We made it.
你是在哭吗
Are you crying?
没有 笨蛋
No, ding-dong.
只是灰尘进了眼睛
It's just a little dusty out here.
行了 变异原
Okay, the mutagen is now
已经进了他的血液循环
entering his bloodstream.
斯普林特大师
Master Splinter?
没反应
Nothing's happening.
为什么还没起作用
Why isn't it working yet?
麦奇…
Mikey...
麦奇 靠近点
Mikey, come closer.
他说什么 说什么
What did he say? What did he say?
他说"把你的膝盖从我胸口上拿开"
He said, "Please get your knee off my chest."
老师
Sensei!
你活过来了
You're alive!
起作用了
It worked!
对不起 一切都是我的错
I'm sorry. This was all my fault.
你说得对
You were right.
我们还没准备好
We weren't ready.
不
No.
是我没准备好放开你们
It was I who wasn't ready to let you go.
你们只需要去发现
All you needed was to discover
你们真正的力量在于彼此团结信任
that your true power lies in believing in one another.
你终于来了
There she is.
纽约的秘密武器
New York's secret weapon.
你胳膊怎么样了 弗恩
How's your arm, Vern?
跟人打架是用不上了
Well, it wouldn't be much use in a fight.
虽然之前我也不怎么会打架 但是…
Not that I was much use before, but...
- 你买了新车吗 - 对
- Did you get a new car? - Yeah.
这是新的芬威克专车
You're looking at the new Fenwick Express.
不错吧
Pretty sweet, huh?
其实还升级了呢
Kind of an upgrade.
之前上班开的车毁了
I figured I'd need new wheels
我觉得我需要辆新车
after my old work vehicle went boom.
好吧 是第六频道给我买的
Yeah, Channel 6 gave it to me.
他们还说不要刮伤一丝一毫
They said don't put a scratch on it,
不过 一个人还能被雷劈中两回不成
but, like, lightning's going to strike twice?
你叫我来就是想跟我说这个吗
So, is that why you called me here,
跟我说你的新车
to talk about your new car?
我知道你不是那种
I know that you're not exactly
带去高档餐厅吃一顿就开心的人
a fancy restaurant kind of girl,
所以我就想 可能你更喜欢大半夜
so I figured a creepy underpass in an abandoned neighborhood
来一个废旧街区的高架桥下
in the middle of the night was more your speed.
我想让你觉得自在些
I wanted you to be comfortable.
DJ麦奇来啦
DJ Mikey in the house!
你们怎么来了
What are you guys doing here?
你帮我们保守秘密 我们该跟你道声谢
We figured we owed you a thanks for keeping our secret.
把我们的事曝光 你肯定能得到不少好处
You had a lot to gain from telling people about us,
但是你一直挺我们
but you had our backs.
因为我们是一家人 拉斐
Yeah, 'cause that's what family's for, Raph.
现在你们也开车行动了吗
So you guys are driving now?
是啊老兄 我把这家伙彻底改造了一番
Yeah, man. I pimped this bad boy out.
上面装了42英寸等离子电视 可以看NBA所有比赛
Got a 42-inch plasma with the NBA package,
还有绵绵冰制冰机 7.1数字立体音响
shave ice machine, 7.1 digital surround sound.
来听听贝斯音 老兄
Check the bass, bra.
不好意思 我还不是很熟悉各种按键功能
My bad. I'm still figuring out the buttons.
那可是我新买的芬威克专车
That was my new Fenwick Express!
我…我刚买的啊
I just... I just got that.
我们最好离开这里
We better get out of here.
需要我们送你们回家吗
Want a ride home?
算了 我们还是坐地铁吧
You know what? I think we're gonna take the subway.
我们一起去坐地铁
We're going to take the subway.
你确定吗
You sure?
我刚写了一首很好听的歌呢
I got a real nice song that's all cued up.
- 专门为你 美女 - 不要
- It's special, girl. - No, don't.
- 也为我们大家 - 行了 麦奇
- For us. - Come on, Mikey.
不不不 麦奇 你答应我们不唱的
No, no, no, Mikey, you promised.
*想象你我二人在一起*
*Imagine me and you, I do*
*我日夜都想念着你*
*I think about you day and night*
*只有想你才是…*
*It's only right to think about...*
我这不是有很大进步了吗
I'm making really good headway!
你闭嘴 麦奇
Shut up, Mikey!
*除你之外我谁都不会去爱*
*I can't see me loving nobody but you*
*你是我一生的挚爱*
*For all my life*
*每当你我在一起*
*When you're with me, baby*
*我的天空便一碧如洗*
*The skies'll be blue for all my life!*